Guide to the Kathryn Hulme Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1924-78; Series I; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Annie's Captain
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
      - Resumé, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Draft typescript of Preface and Chapter 1, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Typescript, annotated by Hulme and Ted Weeks, [1960] (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Galley proofs, [1960?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Reviews (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: Series IV, Box 27, folder 629.
    - Kokee Cabin Log-Book
      See: Series IV, Box 27, folder 630 and Box 28, folder 631.
    - Look a Lion in the Eye
      - Research notes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Typescript (photocopy) draft, annotated by Solita Solano, [1972?] (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
      - Typescript, corrected by Hulme, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
      - Setting typescript, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20-24)
      - Setting typescript (photocopy), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25-29)
      - Galley proofs, [1974] (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Publicity and reviews, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        See also: Series IV, Box 28, folder 632.
    - The Nun's Story
      - Notes, revisions, and deletion lists, 1954-55 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Setting typescript, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 33-44)
      - Publicity, 1957-60, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Reviews, 1956-60, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46-49)
      - Scrapbook, 1956-57, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 50-51)
        See also: Series IV, Box 29, folder 633.
    - The Nun's Story (film version)
      - Scenarios and notes (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Filmscript by Robert Anderson, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Publicity, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 54-58)
      - Reviews, 1959, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 59-60)
        See also: Series IV, Box 29, folder 634.
    - Someday He'll Sing For You
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Typescript (photograph), [1969] (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - They Called Her Willikoki
      - Typescript (photocopy), [1976] (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Undiscovered Country
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Typescript, "Author's copy, corrected by Solita Solano", [1965?] (Box 4, Folder 65-73)
      - Typescript pages, corrected by Hulme, [1965?] (Box 4, Folder 74-75)
      - Setting typescript, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 76-88)
      - Forward to the German translation, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - Publicity and reviews, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 90)
        See also: Series IV, Box 30, folder 635.
    - We Lived As Children
      - Review, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - The Wild Place
      - "Round robin letters"-early drafts, 1945-48 (Box 5, Folder 92-96)
      - "D. P. Camp Diary", 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - Reviews, 1953-54 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - See also: Series IV, Box 30, folder 636.
  - ARTICLES
    - "Are You Cooking?", 1951 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Ask Mr. Foster publicity:
      - "American Spas", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - "Notes from a Mexican Diary", 1932-41 (Box 5, Folder 101-102)
      - "The Story behind the Question Mark" (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - "A Candle for My Mother", 1957 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - "Charlotte Mack Remembered", 1967 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - "Do Good and Disappear", 1957 (Box 6, Folder 106-07)
    - "Father Damien's Village", 1958 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - "Meetings with Remarkable Men", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 109-10)
    - "My Weekend with a Shearwater", 1962 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - "Paradise Isn't Quite Enough", [1958] (Box 6, Folder 112)
      See also: Series IV, Box 30, folder 637.
    - "Plum Crazy", 1959, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 113-14)
    - "The Real Sister Luke", 1956 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      See also: Series IV, Box 30, folder 638.
    - "River of Light... Lourdes", 1958 (Box 6, Folder 116)
      See also: Series IV, Box 30, folder 639.
    - "The Robert Allerton Story", [1978] (Box 6, Folder 117-19)
    - "The Timeless Kauai Swamp", 1965, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 120-22)
    - "The Wild Dog of Wailua Finds a Home", 1965, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 123-24)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified writings, 1924-66, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 125-26)
- Professional Correspondence, 1940-81; Series II; 3.5; (9 boxes)
  Series II, Professional Correspondence, fills boxes 7-15 of the Kathryn Hulme Papers. Material from publishers and her literary agency is arranged alphabetically by the name of organization, and then chronologically. This is followed by fan mail, which is arranged alphabetically by book title, and then chronologically. "Public appearances" and "declined invitations" are both organized chronologically.
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1953-68 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press, 1953-81 (Box 7, Folder 128-61)
  - Brandt and Brandt
    - Correspondence, 1940-56 Sept (Box 8, Folder 162-84)
    - Correspondence, 1956 Oct-1957 (Box 9, Folder 185-210)
    - Correspondence, 1958-62 (Box 10, Folder 211-50)
    - Correspondence, 1963-81, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 251-86)
    - Financial Statements, 1953-74 (Box 12, Folder 287-308)
    - Financial Statements, 1975-81 (Box 13, Folder 309-14)
    - Contracts, 1956-81 (Box 13, Folder 315-26)
  - Little, Brown, and Co., 1953-74 (Box 13, Folder 327-33)
  - Reader's Digest Condensed Books, 1956-60 (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Fan Mail
    - Annie's Captain, 1961-69 (Box 14, Folder 335-38)
    - Look a Lion in the Eye, 1974-76 (Box 14, Folder 339)
    - The Nun's Story, 1956-68, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 340-55)
    - Undiscovered Country, 1966-75, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 356-61)
    - We Lived As Children, 1962,1976 (Box 14, Folder 362)
    - The Wild Place, 1953-69 (Box 14, Folder 363-64)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-68, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 365-66)
  - Public Appearances, 1953-74, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 367-74)
  - Invitations declined, 1956-74, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 375-78)
- Personal Correspondence, 1929-81; Series III; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series III contains four boxes of alphabetically arranged correspondence. All letters have been placed in chronological order in each folder and individuals have been given separate listings whenever there are five or more items to or from that person.
  - "A" general, 1942-74, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 379)
  - Aleek, Nancy, 1976-77, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 380)
  - Alward, Cedric and Katherine, 1960-69, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 381)
  - America. National Catholic Weekly Review, 1956-59 (Box 16, Folder 382)
  - Anderson, Margaret, 1937-72, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 383-86)
  - Anderson, Maxwell, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 387)
  - Anderson, Robert, 1957-78, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 388)
  - "B" general, 1956-77, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 389-91)
  - Bank of Hawaii, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 392)
  - Barnes, Djuna, 1959-66 (Box 16, Folder 393)
  - Beatrice, Sister, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 394)
  - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1975-81 (Box 16, Folder 395-98)
  - Blanke, Henry, 1957-63 (Box 16, Folder 399)
  - Boston University Libraries, 1966-77 (Box 16, Folder 400)
  - Boyle, Kay, 1953-66 (Box 16, Folder 401-03)
  - Brandt, Carol
    See: Series II
  - Brandt, Erd, 1957-60 (Box 16, Folder 404)
  - Brown Shop, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 405)
  - Bry, Lois, 1968-71 (Box 16, Folder 406)
  - "C" general, 1954-81, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 407-08)
  - Catholic World, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 409)
  - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1956-57 (Box 16, Folder 410)
  - Claire-Madeleine, Sister, 1957-61 (Box 16, Folder 411)
  - Clark, Elizabeth, 1953-77 (Box 16, Folder 412)
  - Cloud, Dudley H.
    See: Box 7, folders 128-43, Atlantic Monthly Press
  - Cody, Msgr. Joseph F., 1957-60 (Box 16, Folder 413)
  - Courtney, Father Humphrey, M.S.C, 1960-69 (Box 17, Folder 414-15)
  - Cowell, Sidney (Mrs. Henry), 1957 (Box 17, Folder 416)
  - Cozzens, Bernice Baumgarten (Box 17, Folder 417-23)
    See also: Boxes 8-10, folders 162-228, Brandt and Brandt.
  - "D" general, 1953-79 (Box 17, Folder 424)
  - Davidson, Louise, 1960-66 (Box 17, Folder 425)
  - deMille, Agnes, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 426)
  - Dymphna, Sister, 1957-59 (Box 17, Folder 427)
  - "E" general, 1956-80 (Box 17, Folder 428)
  - "F" general, 1956-79 (Box 17, Folder 429)
  - Ferrer, Mel, 1959-65 (Box 17, Folder 430)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1960-80 (Box 17, Folder 431-32)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1944-68 (Box 17, Folder 433)
  - Frost, Genia, 1929-71 (Box 17, Folder 434)
  - "G" general, 1957-78, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 435)
  - Gallup, Donald
    See: Box 16 folders 395-98, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
  - Gardiner, Father Harold C.
    See: Box 16, folder 382, America: National Catholic Weekly Review
  - Glamour, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 436)
  - Goldwyn, Samuel, Jr., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 437)
  - Griffin, John Howard, 1956,1959 (Box 17, Folder 438)
  - "H" general, 1954-75 (Box 17, Folder 439-440)
  - Habets, Marie-Louise, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 441)
  - Hepburn, Audrey, 1957-61 (Box 17, Folder 442)
  - Higby, Eleanor, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 443)
  - Hills, Mathilda, 1971,1981 (Box 17, Folder 444)
  - Hulme, Allen, 1956-67, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 445)
  - Hulme, Philip, 1956-62, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 446-47)
  - "I" general, 1953-68 (Box 18, Folder 448)
  - "J" general, 1956-69 (Box 18, Folder 449)
  - Jamison, David and Frank, 1956-73 (Box 18, Folder 450)
  - Jensen, Mary, 1963-67 (Box 18, Folder 451)
  - "K" general, 1947-69, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 452)
  - Keith, Agnes Newton, 1966-79 (Box 18, Folder 453)
  - Koshland, William
    See: Box 7, folder 127, Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
  - "L" general, 1954-78, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 454-56)
  - Levesque, Angele, 1957,1975-77 (Box 18, Folder 457)
  - Ligon, Barbara, 1975-77 (Box 18, Folder 458)
  - Loring, Charles, 1957-61 (Box 18, Folder 459)
  - "M" general, 1954-80, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 460-61)
  - McGurdy, Lucille, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 462)
  - Monhoff, Frederick R., 1966-74 (Box 18, Folder 463)
  - Monhoff, Mrs. Frederick
    See: Box 17 folders 431-32, Flanner, Hildegarde.
  - "N" general, 1954-74 (Box 18, Folder 464)
  - "O" general, 1953-67, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 465)
  - "P" general, 1948-79, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 466)
  - Paradise of the Pacific, 1961-67 (Box 18, Folder 467)
  - P.E.N., 1956-57 (Box 18, Folder 468)
  - Pukui, Mary Kawena, 1946,1964 (Box 18, Folder 469)
  - "Q" general, 1957-62 (Box 18, Folder 470)
  - "R" general, 1952-75, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 471)
  - Reprint Society, Ltd., 1958 (Box 18, Folder 472)
  - Rohrer, Alice, 1949,1956 (Box 18, Folder 473)
  - Rosenberg Foundation, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 474)
  - "S" general, 1953-74, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 475-76)
  - San Francisco Maritime Museum, 1954-73 (Box 18, Folder 477)
  - Saurma, Märielisa, Gräfin von, 1967-68 (Box 18, Folder 478)
  - Savage, Father Derrick, 1969-72 (Box 18, Folder 479)
  - Schlessinger, Charles
    See: Box 11, folders 251-86, Brandt and Brandt.
  - Seaver, Edwin
    See: Box 13, folders 327- 33, Little, Brown, and Co.
  - Shivers, Alfred, 1978-79 (Box 18, Folder 480)
  - Sign. National Geographic Magazine, 1956-57 (Box 18, Folder 481)
  - Simon and Schuster, 1952-60 (Box 18, Folder 482)
  - Slemons, Anne, 1933-35,60-62,n.d. (Box 18, Folder 483)
  - Solano, Solita, 1951-75, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 484-93)
  - Staveley, Annie Lou, 1976, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 494)
  - "T" general, 1957-80 (Box 19, Folder 495)
  - Thurber, James, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 496)
  - Troxel, Dorothy, 1975-77, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 497-500)
  - "U" general, 1959-62 (Box 19, Folder 501)
  - "V" general, 1958-67 (Box 19, Folder 502)
  - Vogt, Helene, 1970-78 (Box 19, Folder 503)
  - "W" general, 1939-77, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 504)
  - Weeks, Edward
    See: Box 7, folders 128-61, Atlantic Monthly Press. And Boxes 8-11, folders 162-286, Brandt and Brandt.
  - Whitcomb, Donald, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 505)
  - Wiltgen, Father Ralph, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 506)
  - "Y" general, 1957-68 (Box 19, Folder 507)
  - Zinnemann, Fred, 1957-64 (Box 19, Folder 508)
  - Zinnemann, Renee, 1958-63 (Box 19, Folder 509)
  - Unidentified, 1947-77, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 510-512)
- Family Papers, Dates 1846-1987; Series IV; 9.5; (14 boxes)
  Boxes 20-33 hold Series IV, Family Papers. Papers in Boxes 20-26 have been arranged alphabetically by person and then by subject. Oversize material for the Kathryn Hulme Papers is located in Boxes 27-33 and has been placed in series order.
  - Anderson, Margaret: "James Joyce," newspaper article, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 513)
  - Bolles, Benjamin Franklin (1814-84)
    - Correspondence, 1881-83 (Box 20, Folder 514)
    - Purchase orders, 1846 (Box 20, Folder 515)
  - Bolles, Benajamin Franklin (1843-87)
    - Correspondence, 1884-85 (Box 20, Folder 516)
  - Bolles, E.C.
    - Correspondence, 1883, 1888 (Box 20, Folder 517)
  - Boyle, Kay
    - Affidavits presented to H. U. A. C., 1954 (Box 20, Folder 518)
    - Eulogy for Joseph Franckenstein, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 519)
  - Cavarly, Frank B.
    - Correspondence, 1895, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 520)
    - Scrapbook, 1896-98 (Box 20, Folder 521)
    - "Scrapbook items" (Box 20, Folder 522-25)
      See also: Box 31, folders 640-41.
  - Cavarly, John Marshall (1832-95)
    - Correspondence, 1863-90 (Box 20, Folder 526)
    - Letters of recommendation, photocopies, 1857-81 (Box 20, Folder 527)
    - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 528-29)
    - Orders, photocopies, 1864-87 (Box 20, Folder 530)
    - Papers, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 531)
    - Parole from the C.S. of A., photocopy, 1863 (Box 20, Folder 532)
    - Receipts, 1862-63 (Box 20, Folder 533)
  - Cavarly, John Mansfield (1874-1911)
    - Letter and a clipping, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 534)
  - Dahl, Elizabeth: Diary, 1925-26 (Box 21, Folder 535)
  - Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovich
    - Gurdjieff Foundation: pamphlets (Box 21, Folder 536)
    - Gurdjieff Foundation of California:, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 537)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1944-80, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 538)
    - Remembering Pyotr Denisovich Ouspensky pamphlets, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 539)
  - Habets, Marie-Louise
    - Identification cards, 1949,1951 (Box 21, Folder 540)
    - Interview: The Way, 1957 Feb (Box 21, Folder 541)
    - Papers: nursing career, 1945-63 (Box 21, Folder 542)
    - Papers: refugee and relief work, 1945-51 (Box 21, Folder 543-44)
    - Passport, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 545)
    - Printed: "Où fleurit la Charite ...", 1953 (Box 21, Folder 546)
    - Printed: "Soeur Marie Louis", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 547)
  - Heap, Jane: obituary, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 548)
  - Henzen, Elizabeth Cavarly: reminiscences and notes (Box 21, Folder 549)
  - Hulme, Julia Cavarly (1870-1949)
    - Diary, 1889-90 (Box 21, Folder 550)
    - Memorabilia, 1880 (Box 21, Folder 551)
  - Hulme, Kathryn
    - Addresses, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 552)
    - Awards and certificates, 1957-74 (Box 21, Folder 553-54)
    - Biographical sketches, 1957-64 (Box 21, Folder 555)
    - Financial Papers
      - Employers' Federal Tax Records, 1957-58, 1978-80 (Box 21, Folder 556)
      - Hawaiian Escrow, Ltd., 1960-66 (Box 21, Folder 557)
      - Income Tax returns, 1938-74 (Box 21, Folder 558-61)
      - Insurance, 1978-80 (Box 21, Folder 562)
      - Medical Expenses, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 563)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 564-65)
      - Partnership agreement, 1959-60 (Box 21, Folder 566)
    - Identification cards, 1943-70 (Box 22, Folder 567)
    - Kauai
      - Botanical notes, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 568)
      - Friends of the Lihue Public Library, 1955-71, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 569)
      - Kauai Conference on Culture and the Arts, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 570)
      - Kauai Council on the Arts and Culture, 1965-67 (Box 22, Folder 571-72)
      - Kauai Historical Society, 1969-80 (Box 22, Folder 573)
      - Kauai Humane Society, 1971, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 574)
      - Kauai Library and Museum Association Ltd.
        - Accountants' reports, 1965-71 (Box 22, Folder 575)
        - Minutes, 1966-74 (Box 22, Folder 576)
        - Reports and records, 1963-73 (Box 22, Folder 577)
      - Kauai Museum
        - Circulating library records, 1966-76 (Box 22, Folder 578)
        - Dedication, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 579)
        - Financial statements, 1966-76 (Box 22, Folder 580)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1966-74 (Box 22, Folder 581)
      - National Geographic, 1977 Nov (Box 22, Folder 582)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1964-76, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 583-84)
      - Plum harvesting: notes and permit, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 585)
      - Speech festival, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 586)
      - Wailua homesteads, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 587)
        See also: Boxes 32-33, folders 642-44.
    - Memorabilia
      - Awards
        - Author's Club of Los Angeles, [1957?] (Box 23, Folder 588)
        - Commonwealth Club, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 589)
        - Los Angeles Times "Woman of the Year", 1956 (Box 24, Folder 590)
    - Menu, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 591)
    - Peace Medal, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 592)
    - Plaque, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 593)
    - Shipyard identification badge, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 594)
    - Stone from Troy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 595)
    - UNRRA patch and pin, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 596)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 597-98)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1953-81, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 599-602)
    - Pacific Tropical Botanical Garden, 1975-78 (Box 25, Folder 603)
    - Passports, 1945-78 (Box 25, Folder 604)
    - Printed
      - Albatross, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 605)
      - The American Neptune, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 606)
      - Kemble, J. H.: Sidewheelers Across the Pacific, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 608)
      - King, T. D.: Thumbnail Celestial Navigation, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 609)
      - The San Francisco Maritime Museum, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 610)
      - Sea Breezes, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 611)
    - Refugee and Relief Work
      - Displaced Persons Act of 1948, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 612)
      - Employment records: UNNRA, 1945-47 (Box 25, Folder 613)
      - Employment records: IRO, 1947-53 (Box 25, Folder 614)
      - Examination protocols, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 615)
      - Komski, Jan: Za drutani, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 616)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1946-63 (Box 26, Folder 617)
      - Papers, 1946-51, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 618)
      - Repatriation and resettlement reports, 1946, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 619)
      - Synod of the Ukrainian Autokephal Orthodox Church, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 620)
      - Transcripts of Robert St. John's radio broadcasts, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 621)
      - Wdowiszewski, Czelaw: drawing, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 622)
      - Wildflecken: papers and reports, 1946-47 (Box 26, Folder 623-24)
    - Vital records, 1901-42, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 625)
  - Hulme, Minne Gertrude: clipping, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 626)
  - Solano, Solita: "Nancy Cunard: Brave Poet, Indomitable Rebel", [1966] (Box 26, Folder 627)
  - Vogt, Helene: illustrations for Arab Interlude, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 628)
  - Oversize
    - Annie's Captain, 1961-62 (Box 27, Folder 629)
    - Kokee Cabin Log-Book I, 1967-73 (Box 27, Folder 630)
    - Kokee Cabin Log-Book II, 1974-77 (Box 28, Folder 631)
    - Look a Lion in the Eye: reviews and publicity, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 632)
    - The Nun's Story: reviews and publicity, 1956-57 (Box 29, Folder 633)
    - The Nun's Story (film version): reviews and publicity, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 634)
    - Undiscovered Country: reviews and publicity, 1966-67 (Box 30, Folder 635)
    - The Wild Place: reviews and publicity, 1953-55 (Box 30, Folder 636)
    - "Paradise Isn't Quite Enough," in Holiday, 1969 Apr (Box 30, Folder 637)
    - "The Real Sister Luke," in American Weekly, 1956 Dec 20 (Box 30, Folder 638)
    - "River of Light.. .Lourdes," in Vogue, 1958 Jan (Box 30, Folder 639)
  - Cavarly, Frank B.
    - Shipping scrapbook, 1899-1911 (Box 31, Folder 640)
    - Theatre scrapbook, [1898-1900] (Box 31, Folder 641)
  - Hulme, Kathryn
    - Kauai scrapbooks, 1960-66 (Box 32, Folder 642-43)
    - Kauai scrapbooks, 1967-77 (Box 33, Folder 644)
  - Photograph album: Wildflecken, 1945-47 (Box 33, Folder 645)
- Photographs, 1873-1974; Series V; 4.75; (20 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs, is housed in boxes 34-53 and is divided into four sections: Albums, People, Places and Publicity Photographs. Albums, People, and Places have been arranged alphabetically by person and subject.
  - ALBUMS
    - Cavarly family Christmas album, 1873 (Box 34, Folder 646)
    - Europe: general
      - Germany, [1947?] (Box 35, Folder 647)
      - Germany, France, Switzerland, and Belgium, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 648)
      - Germany, Italy, and the Mediterranean, 1948-49 (Box 37, Folder 649)
      - "Tour", [1949?] (Box 38, Folder 650)
      - "Tour", [1949?] (Box 39, Folder 651)
      - "Vacation, I", 1949-50 (Box 40, Folder 652)
      - "Vacation, II", 1949-50 (Box 41, Folder 653)
      - Souvenir of Berchtesgaden, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 654)
    - Europe: relief and refugee work/ D.P. Camps
      - Wurzburg and Wildflecken camp, 1945-46 (Box 43, Folder 655)
      - Kleinheubach and Aschaffenburg camps, 1945-47 (Box 44, Folder 656)
      - Aschaffenburg camp, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 657)
      - "UNNRA and IRO work, vol. I", 1947-48 (Box 45, Folder 658)
      - "UNNRA and IRO work, vol. II", 1950 (Box 46, Folder 659)
      - Resettlement trip, Bremerhaven to Australia (Box 47, Folder 660)
        See also: Series IV, Box 33, folder 645.
    - Mexico, 1932 (Box 48, Folder 661)
    - United States of America
      - Cross-country tour, [1951?] (Box 49, Folder 662-63)
      - Western tour, 1954-56 (Box 50, Folder 664)
  - PEOPLE
    - Bolles, Benjamin Franklin, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 665)
    - Bolles, "Great-grandmother" (Box 51, Folder 666)
    - Brehmer, Robert, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 667)
    - Burke, Daniel, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 668)
    - Cavarly, Annie Bolles, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 669-70)
    - Cavarly, Frank B., [ca. 1900] (Box 51, Folder 671)
    - Cavarly, John Mansfield, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 672-73)
    - Cavarly, John Mansfield and Cavarly, Annie Bolles (Box 51, Folder 674)
    - Cavarly, John Mansfield, jr., and Cavarly, Frank B. (Box 51, Folder 675)
    - Cavarly, May, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 676)
    - [Cavarly?], unidentified, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 677-78)
    - Chambers family, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 679)
    - Courtney, Fr. Humphrey, 1960, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 680)
    - Cowell, Sidney, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 681)
    - Cozzens, Beatrice Baumgarten: "Shadowbrook", 1959 (Box 51, Folder 682)
    - Craig, Robert, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 683)
    - Cuny, David A., n.d. (Box 51, Folder 684)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1947, ca. 1960 (Box 51, Folder 685)
    - Habets, Marie Louise, [1963] (Box 51, Folder 686)
    - Habets, Marie-Louise, and Hulme, Kathryn, [ca. 1956] (Box 51, Folder 687)
    - Henzel, Elizabeth Cavarly, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 688)
    - Hulme, Julia Cavarly, 1939, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 689)
    - Hulme, Kathryn, [1920-79?] (Box 51, Folder 690-93)
    - Hulme, Kathryn: Authors League of America (Box 51, Folder 694)
    - Hulme, Kathryn, and friends, [1930-79?] (Box 51, Folder 695-99)
    - Hulme, Philip, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 700)
    - [Hulme family?], n.d. (Box 52, Folder 701-02)
    - "Joseph Zukin Employees' Dance", 1921 Feb 4 (Box 52, Folder 703)
    - Larsen, Dorothy Hulme (Box 52, Folder 704)
    - Leakey, Louis and Mary (Box 52, Folder 705)
    - LeBlanc, Georgette, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 706)
    - [Molber, G.?], n.d. (Box 52, Folder 707)
    - Saurma, Marielisa, Gräfin von, 1967-68 (Box 52, Folder 708)
    - Solano, Solita, 1952, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 709)
    - Stephens, Henry Morse, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 710)
    - Weeks, Ted, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 711)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 712-15)
  - PLACES
    - France: Lourdes, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 716)
    - France: [Orgeval?], n.d. (Box 52, Folder 717)
    - Mexico, [1932?] (Box 52, Folder 718)
    - United States of America
      - California, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 719-20)
      - Hawaii, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 721)
      - Pennsylvania: Hulmeville, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 722)
    - Unidentified and miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 723-25)
  - PUBLICITY